世界各地的人們每天花費 160 億小時
Every day, people around the world
spend 16 billion hours
關於無酬護理工作——
on unpaid care work --
為家人做飯，為他們打掃衛生，
cooking for their families,
cleaning up after them,
照顧孩子和年長的親戚
caring for children and older relatives
以及所有其他日常家務勞動。
and all the other routine household tasks.
這些活動在每個國家、每時每刻都在發生
These activities are happening all day,
at every hour, in every country
世界各地。
around the world.
但因為許多人並沒有因為這份工作而獲得報酬
But because many
don't get paid for this work,
我們大多數人都認為這是理所當然的。
most of us take it for granted.
[我們的工作方式]
[The Way We Work]
護理工作是所有任務和雜務的總稱
Care work is a catch-all term
for all the tasks and chores
是為他人服務而完成的。
that are done in service of other people.
有些護理工作是有報酬的，例如醫藥、護理或保姆，
Some care work is paid, like medicine,
nursing or being a nanny,
但大量的工作是免費的。
but a tremendous amount is done for free.
而這種無償照護工作絕大多數是由女性完成的。
And this unpaid care work
is overwhelmingly done by women.
我的一生中有過很多女人
There have been so many
women in my own life
誰提供有償和無償照護工作。
who provided both paid
and unpaid care work.
我的母親和我的祖母在她面前。
My mother and my grandmother before her.
埃斯瓦里（Eswari）在我祖母的最後幾年照顧她。
Eswari, who was nursing
my grandmother in her final years.
帕特里夏，當我出差時照顧我的孩子。
Patricia, who cares for my children
when I travel for work.
我也曾是無薪照顧者
And I've been an unpaid caregiver, too,
照顧我的直系親屬，
caring for my immediate family,
也花了幾個月的時間照顧生病的朋友和他們的孩子
but also spending several months
caring for ailing friends, their children
和我父親最後的日子。
and my dad in his last days.
我開始意識到無償照護工作
I've come to realize that unpaid care work
使所有其他工作成為可能。
makes all other work possible.
新冠肺炎疫情期間，
During the COVID pandemic,
隨著學校的關閉和醫療保健系統的壓力，
with the closure of schools
and the strain on the health care system,
用於無償照護和家務勞動的時間增加了一倍
the amount of time spent on unpaid care
and domestic work doubled
對於工作的父母來說。
for working parents.
這對世界各地的女性來說都是一場災難。
This has been a disaster
for women around the world.
加劇壓力
Compounding the stress
並將數百萬人完全趕出有償勞動市場。
and pushing millions out of the paid
labor market altogether.
它將進步的時間倒退了幾十年。
It set the clock back
on progress by decades.
但同時，
But at the same time,
疫情也讓護理工作變得引人注目。
the pandemic also made care work visible.
它出現在我們 Zoom 通話的背景中
It showed up in the background
of our Zoom calls
以及我們需要限制加班。
and in our need to limit overtime.
許多工作場所能夠整合
And so many workplaces
were able to integrate
甚至慶祝這個新的現實。
and even celebrate this new reality.
現在，我們有一個難以置信的機會
Right now, we have
an incredible opportunity
認識我們生活中的護理工作，為我們自己重新定義它
to recognize the care work in our lives,
reframe it for ourselves
並建立更適應它的工作場所。
and build workplaces that are much
more accommodating of it.
我們可以從這裡開始。
And here's where we can start.
如果您是提供照護的人，
If you are someone providing care,
你能做的最重要的事情就是為自己和他人命名。
the biggest thing you can do is name it
for yourself and for others.
護理工作。
Care work.
這不是一種幹擾
It's not a distraction
如果你適合有償就業。
if you're fitting it
around paid employment.
你沒有“休息”
You're not "taking a break"
如果你在休假期間照顧有需要的人。
if you’re on sabbatical
caring for someone in need.
這是真正的、關鍵的工作
This is real, critical work
這可能會令人筋疲力盡、令人沮喪甚至無聊。
that can be exhausting,
frustrating and even boring.
允許自己感受所有你會感受到的情緒
Give yourself permission to feel
all of the emotions you'd feel
如果工作伴隨著薪水。
if the work came
accompanied by a paycheck.
當你和你的經理談論這件事時
And when you're talking
to your manager about it,
不覺得你需要道歉。
don't feel like you need to apologize.
請記住，這是生活的事實，
Remember, this is a fact of life,
並儘可能明確地表達您的需求。
and be as explicit as you can
about your needs.
需要在家待三個月嗎
Do you need three months at home
或者您需要在周二早上進行長期預約嗎？
or do you need Tuesday mornings
for a standing appointment?
作為一名護理人員，
As a caregiver,
認識到您在這項工作中獲得的技能也很重要。
it's also important to recognize
the skills that you gain doing this work.
提供護理涉及很多事情——
There is so much involved
with giving care --
處理運輸、物流、
handling transport, logistics,
解釋醫療圖表，管理財務。
interpreting medical charts,
managing financials.
這些都是寶貴的技能
These are valuable skills
與各種背景相關的內容。
that are relevant
to all kinds of contexts.
因此，如果您有工作，請以這種方式向您的同事提供照顧。
So if you have a job, frame caregiving
to your colleagues that way.
如果您正在尋找有償工作，
And if you’re looking for paid work,
不要把它當作你生活中的一個巨大的空白。
don't treat it as a big empty
gap in your life.
將其放在您的簡歷中並概述您從中獲得的技能。
Put it on your CV and outline the skills
that you've gained from it.
多工等技能
Skills like multitasking,
專案管理或溝通。
project management or communication.
但當然這不只針對個人
But of course it's not just on individuals
改變更廣泛的世界對護理工作的看法。
to change how the wider world
thinks about care work.
我們也需要雇主進行系統性變革。
We need systemic change
from employers, too.
雇主可以做的最重要的事情
The biggest thing that employers can do
就是給員工騰出空間來談護理工作
is to make space for employees
to talk about care work
不會受到懲罰或被視為不那麼專注或專注。
without being penalized or seen
as less focused or dedicated.
照顧應該是儘早提出的話題
Caregiving should be a topic
that's brought up early
當新員工第一次開始培訓時。
when new employees
first start their training.
工作場所應追蹤並了解護理工作的種類
Workplaces should track and understand
the kind of care work
員工負責
employees are responsible for
需要什麼樣的政策改變才能讓他們的生活變得更好
and what kind of policy changes
are needed to make their lives better
並且更有生產力。
and more productive.
雇主應該確保照顧者不會被忽視
And employers should make sure
that caregivers aren't passed over
僅僅因為他們在家裡的職責而參與關鍵項目或晉升。
for key projects or promotions
just because of their duties at home.
照顧是人類的一個基本面，
Caregiving is such a fundamental
aspect of being human,
然而它卻被人為地從我們的工作生活中清除掉了。
and yet it's so artificially cleansed
from our work lives.
與其把它當作秘密，
Instead of treating it like a secret,
工作場所可以將其公開。
workplaces can bring it out into the open.
當然，工作場所需要提供靈活性
And of course, workplaces
need to offer flexibility
以適應護理人員的生活現實。
to accommodate the lived
realities of caregivers.
對於身為父母的員工來說，
For employees who are parents,
除了育嬰假之外，
in addition to parental leave,
這意味著當孩子生病或放學回家時，允許他們休息。
this means allowing them time off
when kids are sick or home from school.
這意味著讓他們在日曆中建立黑暗區域
It means letting them establish
dark zones in their calendar
放學前後、洗澡時間、睡前儀式
around school drop offs,
bath time, bedtime rituals
並尊重這些界線。
and respecting those boundaries.
這意味著提供遠端工作選項。
It means offering remote work options.
對於照顧老人、病人或殘障的人來說，
For people caring for elders
or those who are sick or disabled,
這意味著給予他們合理的休假時間。
this means giving them
reasonable amounts of leave.
這意味著建立基於里程碑和可交付成果的項目，
It means building projects that are based
on milestones and deliverables,
而不是只依靠頻繁的會議和簽到。
rather than relying on frequent
meetings and check-ins alone.
這意味著非常靈活
It means being really flexible
關於工作何時何地完成。
about when and where the work gets done.
工作場所往往因此蓬勃發展。
And workplaces often thrive as a result.
最後一點。
And one final point.
護理工作是我們經濟中成長最快的部門之一。
Care work is one of the fastest-growing
sectors of our economy.
由於人口增長和老化，
As a result of a growing
and an aging population,
到 2030 年，世界上將有超過 20 億人需要照護。
over two billion people in the world
will need care by 2030.
這意味著現在是時候改變我們照顧他們的方式了。
This means that the time is now to shift
the way we think about caring for them.
人口老化將需要支持。
This aging population
is going to need support.
他們將需要新的解決方案。
They're going to need new solutions.
這意味著創新、就業、新產業。
This means innovations,
jobs, new industries.
許多其他工作都因自動化而消失，
And where many other
jobs are lost to automation,
這是我們人類最擅長的工作
the one job that we're so uniquely
good at as humans
關心其他人類。
is caring for other humans.